Guide to the Reynolds Price Papers, 1927-2010 and undated, bulk 1956-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series (RESTRICTED), 1935-2004 and undated, (92 boxes)
  - Writings by Price Subseries (RESTRICTED), 1946-2003 and undated, (76 boxes)
    - Feasting the Heart (nonfiction, 2000) RESTRICTED (Box WP60)
      - Individual essays
        - Crossing Genders, undated
        - Forty and Counting, undated
        - Summer Vacation, undated
    - A Perfect Friend (novel, juvenile, 2000) RESTRICTED (Box WP62)
      - Typescript drafts, 1999
        - Draft entitled [A Boy and His Elephant], revised 1999 Jan. 25
        - 1999 Mar. 8-29
        - With author's revisions (incomplete), 1999 May 1-25
        - With Eric Larson's notes, 1999 June
        - With notes and revisions by author and unidentified reader, 1999 June-Aug.
        - Fair copy fragment, circa 1999 June-Aug.
        - With author's revisions, 1999 Aug. 3-9
        - Original copyedited typescript, 1999 Aug. 20-Oct., (2 folders)
      - Cover sketches, 1999 Oct. 22
      - Catalog copy, 2000 Feb. 1
      - Sample pages, 2000 Feb. 2, June 20
      - Blues pages (blueprint proofs) with author's revisions, 2000 June
      - Corrected blues pages, 2000 June
      - Jacket proofs, 2000 and undated
      - Jacket illustration for paperback edition, 2002 Jan. 16
      - Sample case for hardback edition, undated
    - A Great Circle (novels, 2001) RESTRICTED (Box WP63)
      - Possible titles: R. Price's Mayfield trilogy
      - Typescripts: four drafts of preface, 2000 June 24-2001 Feb. 7
      - Proof with author's and Bruce Jorgasson's corrections, 2001 May 26-Apr. 6, (5 folders)
      - Design layouts, 2001 Mar. 20
      - Page proofs: miscellaneous corrected pages, 2001 June 14-27
      - Jacket proofs, undated
    - Noble Norfleet (novel, 2002) RESTRICTED (Box WP64)
      - Notes for a novel, 1997 Oct. 15-1999 Dec. 22
      - Typescript drafts, 2000-2001
        - With author's revisions (photocopy), circa 2000 Jan.-June
        - With author's revisions, circa 2000 Jan.-June, (2 folders)
        - With author's revisions, 2000 July 2-17
        - Fair copy, 2000 July
        - Fragment with author's revisions, 2000 July 24
        - Two fragments, fair copy (photocopy), 2000 Aug. 13-27
        - Fragment with author's revisions, 2000 Sept. 5
        - With author's revisions, 2001 Sept. 7-Oct. 26, (Folders 1-3 of 4)
      - Typescript drafts, 2000-2001 (Box WP65)
        - With author's revisions, 2001 Sept. 7-Oct. 26, (Folder 4 of 4)
        - Original copyedited typescript with author's corrections, 2001 Nov.20-Dec.31, (4 folders)
        - Copyedited typescript (photocopy), 2001 Nov. 20-Dec. 31, (Folders 1-3 of 4)
      - Typescript drafts, 2000-2001 (Box WP66)
        - Copyedited typescript (photocopy), 2001 Nov. 20-Dec. 31, (Folder 4 of 4)
        - Manuscript and typescript fragments: revision and additions, 2001 Dec. 21-24
      - Proofs, 2002
        - With author's revisions, 2002 Jan. 25, (2 folders)
        - Master, 2002 Jan. 25, (2 folders)
        - 2002 Jan. 29, (2 folders)
        - 2002 Feb. 19, (Folder 1 of 2)
      - Proofs, 2002 (Box WP67)
        - 2002 Feb. 19, (Folder 2 of 2)
        - Master, second pass with author's changes, 2002 Feb. 19-Mar. 4, (2 folders)
      - Proposed catalog copy, 2001 Sept. 25
      - Jacket illustrations and specifications, 2001-2002
      - Research on Vietnam War casualties, 2002 Feb. 8
      - Jacket proofs, 2002 and undated
      - Typescript, fair copy of chapter one, undated
      - Flap copy, undated
    - A Serious Way of Wondering (nonfiction, 2003) RESTRICTED (Box WP68)
      - Typescripts with author's revisions
        - 2002 June 2-July 5
        - 2002 July 14-27
        - 2002 Aug. 5-13
      - Typescript, fair copy of August 13th revisions, 2002 Aug. 14
      - Typescript with Susan Moldow e-mail comments (missing pp. 154 ff.), circa 2002 Sept., (2 folders)
      - Typescript--first draft and part-titles, 2002 Sept. 22, (2 folders)
      - Typescript, circa 2002 Sept.-Oct., (2 folders) (Box WP69)
      - Copyedited typescript with author's corrections, 2002 Oct. 4-Nov. 22, (2 folders)
      - Page proof with author's corrections, 2002 Dec. 13-2003 Jan. 3
      - Page proof with author's corrections, 2003 Jan. 17-Feb. 7
      - Design layouts, 2002 Dec. 10-12
      - Flap copy--three drafts with author's corrections, 2003 Jan. 9 and undated
      - Jacket proofs, 2003 Mar. 12
      - Ad proof, 2003 Sept. 11
      - D. Moody Smith's notes, 2002-2003
    - The Good Priest's Son (novel, 2005) RESTRICTED (Box WP70)
      - Notes for a novel, 2002 Mar. 23-2003 Mar. 3
      - Typescript entitled "Novel #14," with author's revisions 2003 Jan. 6
      - Typescript with author's revisions, 2003 Sept. 25-Oct. 15, (2 folders)
    - Uncollected poems and poetry notebooks, 1952-1997 and undated RESTRICTED (Box WP71)
      - After Rimbaud, manuscript, 1970 Sept.3
      - The Beasts at Evening, typescript with revisions, 1997 June
      - Clear Day, manuscripts and typescripts, 1989 Nov.
      - A Crazy Thing, typescript, undated
      - Da Unter im Tale, manuscript, 1966 July 6
      - Damon's Epitaph, typescript, undated
      - Damon's Epitaph, galley proof, 1978
      - Du schlank und rein... manuscript, 1966 June 18 and 21
      - A Final Stand, typescript with revisions, 1997 June 10
      - For Ross Macdonald, typescript, undated
      - The Fourth Eclogue of Vergil, manuscripts and typescript, 1972
      - The Gate at Treves, manuscript, 1967 Jan. 24 and May 5
      - Gold Day, typescripts with revisions, 1960 Apr.
      - Honeyed Eyes, typescripts with revisions, undated
      - A Hymn of Jesus, typescript, undated
      - If by Luck, typescript, undated
      - In Me Death, typescript, 1970 Sept. 1 and undated
      - I.R.D., typescript, undated
      - Leopoldskron I and Leopoldskron II, manuscripts, undated
      - Lesbia Slanders Me, typescripts, undated
      - A Message Detained, typescripts with revisions, 1977 and undated
      - Moon Tide, typescripts with revisions, 1990 Nov.
      - One of the palpable... typescript, 1987 May
      - The Pirated Heart, manuscripts, 1959 Sept. 5 and 1970 July 16
      - Rank Tavern, typescript, undated
      - Solo: To the Moon, manuscript, 1960 Feb.
      - Spring Takes the Homeplace, edition published by North Carolina Wesleyan College Press, 1989 Oct. 4
      - A Start: Because I Am, typescript, 1952
      - Les Stupra XLVII, manuscript, undated
      - [Three Poems after Catullus] typescripts, undated
      - To Accompany John Nash's 'The Moat' for R.F.B., page from The Archive, 1955
      - Two Theophanies, typescripts with revisions and proof, 1971 and undated
      - Wednesday, June the Sixth, from Lessons Learned, manuscripts and typescript, 1968 and undated
      - Weeds, typescript, undated
      - You Often Harp, manuscripts and typescript, 1969 Jan. 4 and undated
      - Untitled [Bud's home on its hill...], typescript, 1969 Oct. 23
      - Untitled [ Caelius, our Lesbia.., manuscript and typescript, 1970 Aug. 17
      - Spanish translations of Price poems, for a workshop in New York, circa 1995
      - Miscellaneous untitled poems and fragments, 1951-1989 and undated
      - Notebooks entitled Drafts of Poems
        - 1970-1978
        - 1973-1982
        - 1973-1985
      - Notebook entitled Days and Nights, 1984 Feb.
      - Theophanies: Notebook and loose notes, 1968-1974 and undated
    - Uncollected fiction: short stories, fragments, and notes, 1949-1990 and undated RESTRICTED (Box WP72)
      - Back Before Day, 1989
      - The Heart in Dreams, 1974
      - Holy Places, 1977
      - Road, 1989
      - Short Story (untitled), 1949
      - Time Out, 1990
      - A Way Back, 1987?
      - Correspondence and application materials for Guggenheim Foundation, 1960-1970 and undated
        Contains early but undated manuscripts of the stories A Chain of Love, Michael Egerton, The Anniversary, and Troubled Sleep.
      - Untitled fragments and notes, 1961-1971 and undated
    - Uncollected nonfiction: articles, essays, journals, and reviews, 1950-2003 and undated RESTRICTED (Box WP72)
      - An Actual World, typescript and catalog of paintings, 1993
      - At the Brink--John Beerman, typescript and proof with author's revisions, 2000 Oct. 10-Nov. 16
      - Beatrice and Matthew in the Studio by Katherine Doyle, typescript and corrected proof, 2003 Aug. 26-Sept. 10
      - Belief and Doubt, typescript and notes, 2000 May
      - Bouquet for Leontyne, proof and typescript fragment, 1995 Feb. 6 and undated
      - Carol Anthony, typescript and proof, 1999 July 26, Nov. 24
        See also Printed Materials Series, Miscellaneous Printed Materials Subseries.
      - Christmas Food, 1986
      - Criticism of Concept Magazine, 1958
      - Cyber Time, typescript draft of The Unbeatable Lightness of Keyboards, 1998 Aug. 12
      - Dear Harper: a Letter to a Godchild about God, corrected proof and typescript drafts, 2000 Aug. 14 and undated, (4 folders)
      - Death and Work: Milton's 'Epitaphium Damonis', essay and translation (five drafts of each), 1972 Aug. 21 and undated, (2 folders)
      - An Entire World, typescript, proofs, and supporting materials for exhibit, Academic Eye: Reynolds Price collects Danny Robinette, 2001 and undated
      - An Epic Venture, typescript, undated
      - The Fetish of the 'Real', typescripts (two), 1995 Sept. and undated
      - First Loves--a Preface, typescript, undated
      - The First Printing of Place in Fiction, typescript, 1979 Feb. 25-27
      - First Words, typescript with author's revisions, undated
      - A General Response, typescript, undated
      - A Grounded Life, typescript, undated
      - Grounds to Stand On, typescript, undated
      - A Helpful Sight, typescript with author's revisions, 2001 Jan. 29
      - Imaginative Writing at Duke, manuscript and typescript, undated
      - In Paradise: a Surmise, typescripts, four drafts, 2001 Sept. 14-Oct.1 and undated
      - Interview of Lauritz Melchior, 1950-1951
      - Introduction to Song of Solomon, by Toni Morrison, typescripts and proof, 1995 May 7-June 19 (Box WP73)
      - Jesus of Nazareth: Then and Now, typescripts and proofs, 1999 Oct.-Nov. 27 and undated, (7 folders)
      - John Milton, typescript with author's revisions, 2003 July 9
      - "Larry Kramer's Faggots: an Introduction," typescripts and proof, 2000
      - Last Week's Sets, typescript with author's revisions, undated
      - Leontyne Price, manuscripts and typescript, 1978 Oct. 16 and undated
      - The Look of Hope, revised and fair copy typescripts, 1995 July-Sept. and undated, (5 folders)
      - Looking Back on a Talkative Year, typescript, undated
      - A Lucky Choice, typescript, undated
      - Neighbors and Kin, undated
      - Notes on a visit to Ethel Waters, 1950
      - Oh Cuisine: a Platonic Restaurant, galley proof with author's corrections, 1979 Aug. 8-14
      - On Rachmaninov, typescript, 1999 Jan. 18
      - On Stephen Spender, typescript, 1995 July 17
      - The Only News, 1989, (2 folders)
      - Oracles: Six Versions from the Bible, proof with author's corrections, circa 1976
      - A Platonic Place, manuscript, 1978 Apr. 28
      - Pontius Pilate, typescript, 2000
      - Preface for Caroline Vaughan, manuscript, 1977
      - Preface to Jesus Tales, by Romulus Linney, manuscript, 1980 Aug. 21
      - Preface to Bibliography, manuscripts and typescripts, 1980 Jan. 9-Aug. 30 and undated
      - Prevailing Daylight, 1987
      - Rescued and Strengthened, typescript and correspondence, 1996 June 26-July 15 and undated
      - Reviews
        - Best American Short Stories 1979, manuscripts and typescript, 1979 Sept. 17 and undated
        - Books on Jesus by Gregory C. Riley and Jaroslav Pelikan, typescript, 1998
        - Bruccoli, Matthew, The O'Hara Concern: A Biography of John O'Hara, typescript, 1975 Sept. 25
        - Buechner, Frederick, The Sacred Journey, typescript, undated
        - Campbell, Will D., The Glad River, typescript, undated
        - Clifton, Lucille, Generations: A Memoir, manuscript and typescript, 1975 and undated
        - Coles, Robert, The Secular Mind, proof, 1999
        - Gray, Francine du Plessix, World Without End, notes and manuscripts, 1981 Apr. 20-28 and undated
        - Grimsley, Jim, The Lizard of Tarsus, typescript, 1997
        - Humphrey, William, Farther Off from Heaven, manuscript, 1977 May 2-3
        - Percy, Walker, Love in the Ruins, manuscripts and typescripts, 1971 and undated
        - Percy, Walker, Lancelot, manuscript, 1977
        - Porter, Katherine Anne, Conversations with Katherine Anne Porter, manuscript, 1981 June 6-16 (Box WP74)
        - Pritchett, V. S., Collected Stories, typescript, undated
        - Rorem, Ned, Aqua Fortis, typescript, 1978 Jan. 8
        - Short story collections by Mark Helprin and Elizabeth Spencer, manuscript and typescript, 1981 and undated
        - Welch, James, with Paul Steckler, Killing Custer, typescript, undated
        - Welty, Eudora, Collected Stories, manuscript and typescript, 1980 and undated
        - Welty, Eudora, One Place, One Time, manuscript and proof, 1973 and undated
      - Reynolds Price: About Himself, undated
      - Reynolds Price on Writing in Southern Review, galley proof, circa 1982
      - St. Paul Departing Caesarea, typescript with author's revisions, 1996 June 24
      - Sally Mann, typescript with author's revisions, 2001 June 14
      - Scenes from a Journey, galley proof with author's corrections, 1994 Mar. 21
      - A School for Husbands, typescript with author's revisions, undated
      - Scripture translations, manuscripts and typescripts, 1968-1969
      - A Serious Moment, undated
      - Three Pieces--and a Start--about Race, manuscripts and typescripts, 1969-1971 and undated
      - Two Years Underway: Pages from a Notebook, 1977
      - An Uncharted Storm, typescript with author's revisions, 1995 May 9
      - A Useful Offer, typescript, 1996
      - A Waiting Beauty, typescripts and proofs with author's corrections, 2002 Aug. 1-Sept. 12, (2 folders)
      - Welty, Eudora: untitled short pieces about Welty, including notes for Price's interview of her, a letter essay for Aperture, and drafts of eulogy, 1984, 2001, and undated
      - What Abides, 1989
      - Why I Work, manuscript and two typescripts, 1966 Feb. 2 and undated
      - Why Think of College at All? Why Duke? manuscript and two typescripts, 1969 and undated
      - A Wide Seam of Memory, typescript with author's revisions, 1998 Mar. 29
      - Your Maiden Aunt by No Means, proof and two typescripts, 1995 Mar. 15 and undated
      - Uncollected articles, speeches, reviews, etc., notes, manuscripts, and typescripts, 1968-1972 and undated
        Materials in this folder appear to have been gathered by Price and assigned this folder title in the early 1970s during preparation for his first nonfiction collection, Things Themselves, as some notes and outlines recorded here reflect the final structure of that book. Folder contains a mix of titles later collected in A Common Room; uncollected titles that appear in their own named folders elsewhere in the Reynolds Price Papers; and other manuscripts that are unique to this folder.
      - Untitled and/or incomplete: blurbs, fragments, other short pieces, and notes, 1967-2003 and undated
        Differs from the previous folder in that these items were gathered by the processor of the collection, not the author.
      - Journals and notebooks (bound), 1963, 1989, and undated, (3 folders)
      - Journals and notebooks (loose-leaf), 1961 Dec. and undated
      - Miscellaneous writings, 1961-1990 and undated
      - Student Work, 1946-1953 May Sept. 30, (40 folders) RESTRICTED (Box WP75)
      - Student Work, 1953 Sept.-1958 and undated, (33 folders) RESTRICTED (Box WP76)
      - Student work, 1954
  - Writings by Others Subseries (RESTRICTED), 1935-2004 and undated, (16 boxes)
    Comprised chiefly of manuscripts, drafts, and proofs (some photocopies and some with notes and revisions) of work sent by other authors to Price. Includes poetry, short stories, articles, plays, and novels. Arranged alphabetically by the name of the author and chronologically within each folder if more than one work by the author is included. Proofs of A Bibliography of the Writings of Reynolds Price, by Stuart Wright and James L.W. West are at the end of the series, and various shorter bibliographies of Price's work are arranged chronologically in the last folders.
    - Adcock, Betty (Box WO1)
      - Intervale: New and Selected Poems, 2000
    - Alexander, Corabel
      - All Talk, 1995
      - Crab Bait, 1995
      - It's Probably Nothing, 1995
      - A Far Cry, 1995
      - Homesick, 1995
      - Traps, 1995
    - Applewhite, James
      - City of Infamy, 1970
      - Daytime and Starlight, 1997
    - Auden, W. H.
      - Oratio Creweiana, 1956
    - Barker, Franklin
      - Home Town Girls, 1971
    - Beebe, Chris
      - An Optimist's Journal, 1975, (2 folders)
    - Bell, Madison Smartt
      - Teaching notes on Price for the Goucher College Fiction Workshop, 2000
    - Benay Brothers, The
      - Samurai, undated
    - Bhatia, Lakshmi
      - Precious Pearls, undated
    - Bhuvaneswar, Chaya G.
      - The Last Day, undated, (3 folders)
    - Blackburn, Alexander
      - The Long Habit of Living, essay on William Maxwell Blackburn, circa 1994
    - Bly, Robert (Box WO2)
      - The Lightning Should Have Fallen on Ghalib, undated
    - Boerger, Jeff
      - Desires of a Changing Heart: A Sojourner's Life in the East, 1977
    - Brondoli, Michael
      - Dumb Supper, 1976
      - And Now, Folks, the Dixie Bombshell, undated
    - Bricuth, John
      - Just Let Me Say This About That, 1995
    - Broughton, T. Alan
      - The Skin and All: Songs for the Cruelest Months, 1973-1977
    - Brown, Lightning Allan
      - Poetry and Translation, 1965, 1982-1994
    - Byers, Frederick
      - Silver Falls, 1998
    - Caldwell, Erskine
      - The Sacrilege of Alan Kent, 1936
    - Canin, Ethan
      - For Kings and Planets, 1997
    - Capers, Charlotte
      - Eudora Welty: A Friend's View, 1977
    - Chappell, Fred
      - Le Soleil du Mal, circa 1959
      - Hallowind, 1979
      - For Reynolds, 1986
      - Teacher, undated
    - Clem, Dean
      - Winds of Fury, Circles of Grace, 1996
    - Davenport, Guy and Benjamin Urrutia (Box WO3)
      - The Logia of Yeshua, 1996
    - Davies, W. D.
      - Reflections on Aspects of the Jewish Background of the Gospel of John, 1996
    - Dickey, James
      - Jericho, 1974
      - Land and Water, 1974
      - Reynolds Price, 1981
      - The South Beheld, 1974
      - Memoir of Dickey by his daughter, Bronwen, 1997
    - Donoghue, Denis
      - The Death of Satan, 2000
      - Eudora Welty's Sense of Place, undated
      - The Practice of Reading, 1997 Oct. 10
    - Eberhart, Richard
      - Spring Mountain Climb, 1961
    - Emerson, Donald
      - "Review of A Long and Happy Life," 1962
    - Esty, Jane
      - Green Elegy for a Child, 1970
    - Fellmeth, Michael Quixote
      - A Portrait of Devotion, 1993
    - Fleschner, Paul
      - The Reinvention of Pollyanna Marcase, 2003
    - Foote, Horton
      - A Coffin in Egypt, undated
      - Farewell: A Memoir of a Texas Childhood, undated
      - Genesis of an American Playwright, undated, (3 folders)
      - 1918, undated
    - Fort, Charles (Box WO4)
      - It Is a Fearful Thing to Love What Death Can Touch, 1993
      - Love, 1993
      - Mr. Whore's Ruby Doll, 1993
      - Petrified Forest, 1993
      - Photograph, 1993
      - Poe's Daughter, 1993
      - Superstitious Mountain, 1993
      - The Ugly Man Behind the Little Wood, 1993
      - Understudy, 1993
    - Fox, Jim
      - An Ascent from the Vault, undated
      - The Great Bridge, undated
      - Tar Beach, undated
      - Two Rivers, undated
    - Franck, Derek
      - A Yemeni Passage, 1977
    - Fuller, R.C.
      - Lunging in the Dark: Blindness and Vision, Disappointment and Aspiration in Reynolds Price's Trilogy, undated
    - Garfein, Herschel
      - From and American Book of the Dead: Songs for Mezzo-Soprano and Piano, 1993
    - Garrett, George
      - Little Movie Without a Middle, 1978
    - Grimsley, Jim
      - A Bird of Prey, 1996
      - The Lizard of Tarsus, 1990
    - Guggenheim, Charles
      - Speaking of Reynolds Price: Outtakes from Clear Pictures, 1996 Sept. 25
    - Gurganus, Allan
      - For Jack Fullilove (1917-2000), 1996
    - Harris, Massimilla and C. T. B. Harris
      - A Message in Suffering: A Guide for Understanding the Psychology of Suffering and Transformation, 1991
      - Through the Center of the Self: The Psychology of Suffering and Transformation, 1991
    - Harris, Will
      - Will's Amazing, Fantastic, Hilarious, Horror provoking, Witty, Smart Stories, 2000 July
    - Hassan, Ihab
      - The Expense of Spirit in Postmodern Times: Between Nihilism and Belief, 1997
    - Hauerwas, Stanley
      - In Good Company: preface and first chapter, 1994 Dec. 22
    - Hays, Tommy
      - The Pleasure Was Mine, circa 2004, (Folder 1 of 3)
      - The Pleasure Was Mine, circa 2004, (Folders 2-3 of 3) (Box WO5)
    - Helliker, Kevin
      - The Woodchopper, undated
    - Humphries, Jeff
      - A Bestiary, 1995
      - Beyond the Pleasure Principal, 1977
      - Doctor, Is My Poem Alright?, 1978
      - A Homecoming Suite: Christmas 1977, 1978
      - Sermon Preached to a Mirror at a Christmas Party in the Backwoods, 1978
      - The Madness of Mrs. Crump, 1984
      - The Mirror's Eye, 1984
      - The Conjuror of Color, 1986
      - Poems, 1990
    - Jones, Michael Colby
      - One Hellgate Story, 1998
    - Jones, Paul
      - What the Welsh and Chinese Have in Common, 1990
    - Jorgenson, B. W.
      - 'A Healing Soul' on Reynolds Price's Purgatorial 'Endless Mountains,' undated
      - Pardon and Marriage: Three Stories, undated
    - Justice, Jesse
      - "An Elaborate Dialogue: Fate, Free Will, and Family in Reynolds Price's A Long and Happy Life and Kate Vaiden," 1991
    - Kaufman, Wallace
      - Six Girls, 1959
      - A River Meeting, circa 1964
      - Leukemia, Age 3, undated
    - Kelly, Tom
      - Waiting for Rain, undated
    - Kenna, Michael
      - Ten Poems for a Friend, 1971-1974
    - Kimmel, Haven
      - The Solace of Leaving Early, 2001
    - Kizer, Carolyn
      - Poems, 1980-1986 and undated
    - Kreyling, Michael
      - The Extra, 1988
      - "Men Without Women: Communities of Desire and Race in A Great Circle," 1996
      - Reynolds Price, 1982
    - Landesman, Peter
      - Blood Acre: A Novel, 1997
    - Larson, Eric
      - Bermuda, 2000
      - The Pharisee's Gospel, undated
    - Linney, Romulus (Box WO6)
      - Holy Ghosts, 1972
      - Woman Without a Name, 1985
    - Malouf, Melissa
      - It Had to Be You: The Joan and Ernest Story, 1997
    - Mann, Julian, III
      - The Old Man and the Boy, 1988-1997
    - Manning, Hank
      - Buzzbait, undated
    - Marrs, Suzanne
      - One Writer's Imagination: The Fiction of Eudora Welty, 2002
      - 'The Huge Fateful Stage of the Outside World': Eudora Welty's Life in Politics, undated
    - Massengill, David
      - Picture books, 2001
    - Maunsell, Penelope
      - The Company of the Dead, screenplay of Price's short story, 1997 Mar. 27
    - Maxwell, William
      - The Writer as Illusionist, 1955 Mar. 4
    - McElheny, Sean
      - Lewis and Clark, 1995
    - Meredith, William
      - For Two Lovers in the Canadian Woods a Hundred Years from Now, 1977
    - Millard, Charles
      - Oscar Comes to North Carolina, 1999
    - Modjeska, Lee
      - Keeper of the Night: A Portrait of Life in the Shadow of Death, 1994
    - Moffatt, Jan E.